Mobile: (+98) 935 45 92 265 Email: kam.cpp@gmail.com

## **IN SUMMARY**

As a highly active, motivated and 'computer science loyal' professional software architect with more than of 10 years of experience in development, analysis, design and architecting large scale, national and international projects, my skills are not limited to a specific development platform and my hybrid distributed multi-tier architectural solutions vast from back-end services written in C/C++, Java or Python to front-end applications written in C/C++, Java or even deployed on Web, with consideration of critical architectural factors like Distribution of Data and Computation across multiple domains and clusters, Fault Tolerance of services, High Availability of services, System's Single Points of Failure, overall Performance and Efficiency of the system, Security factors and hardening these factors across the system's domains, etc. As an architect of national projects, I've always faced strict and risky conditions which Security, Data Consistency and Data Correctness have been always a very important factor. As an example, architecture of Distributed ePassport Issuance System (Kawthar System) for Iran's Ministry of Foreign Affairs, was led by me and it is operating world wide in Iran's Consular Offices and Embassies in more than of 70 countries.

## EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCES

April 2015 - Present Noavaran Tejarat Gostar Naeem Chief Technical Officer Senior Software Architect Senior C/C++/Java SE Developer

N.T.Naeem company operates in many fields related to Identity Solutions and Security. As a CTO, I was responsible for every technical decision and management of technical teams, both hardware and software teams. As an architect, I was responsible for architecting projects ranging from middle to large scale systems. Some highlights about my skills and roles are mentioned below.

- I standardized technical procedures with use of Debian-based Linux distros alongside with Git, Jenkins, Redmine Issue Tracker, etc.
- Managing more than 15 software and hardware developers and architects organized in 6 different parallel teams, working on various research and development topics.
- Architecting systems using on-edge technologies and concepts with cooperation of other architects.
- Ability to merge and organize different parts of a heterogeneous system using different toolsets and programming languages and making SOA dominant in architectural decisions.
- Using C/C++, Java SE, Java EE and Python whenever a specific feature or factor acceptance were needed.
- Managing and cooperation with research teams operating in Image Processing, Machine Learning, NLP, Security, Hardware, Cryptography, Mathematics and other computer science related fields.
- Managing, development and leading the architectural teams in various international and national projects like Kawthar ePassport Issuance System, Network Analysis Engine, Data Science Analysis Framework, Consular Portal for Iran's Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Distributed Crawler Engine, ABIS Engines, Biometric Data Enrolment Systems, etc.
- Working on open source projects like Hottentot RPC Framework, C/C++ Corelibs, etc.
- Cooperation and holding sessions with academic people and using the top most national knowledge to supply the research teams.
- Development and leading distributed systems architectures using various systems like Hadoop Family, Cassandra, Redis, ZooKeeper

Page 2 Email: kam.cpp@gmail.com

• Architecting scalable computation engines both vertically and horizontally covering FT, HA, Replication, Consistency concepts.

• Architecting and development of RPC related solutions for ensuring security and performance in all distributed systems.

February 2015 - June 2015 Sahab Pardaz Senior Software Architect Distributed Systems Architect Senior Java SE/EE Developer C++ Developer

Nam dui ligula, fringilla a, euismod sodales, sollicitudin vel, wisi. Morbi auctor lorem non justo. Nam lacus libero, pretium at, lobortis vitae, ultricies et, tellus. Donec aliquet, tortor sed accumsan bibendum, erat ligula aliquet magna, vitae ornare odio metus a mi. Morbi ac orci et nisl hendrerit mollis. Suspendisse ut massa. Cras nec ante. Pellentesque a nulla. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Aliquam tincidunt urna. Nulla ullamcorper vestibulum turpis. Pellentesque cursus luctus mauris.

March 2013 - June 2015 Mojtama E Fanni Tehran (Tehran Technical Complex) Director of Programming Department C++/Java SE/EE Instructor Senior Java EE Developer/Architect

Nam dui ligula, fringilla a, euismod sodales, sollicitudin vel, wisi. Morbi auctor lorem non justo. Nam lacus libero, pretium at, lobortis vitae, ultricies et, tellus. Donec aliquet, tortor sed accumsan bibendum, erat ligula aliquet magna, vitae ornare odio metus a mi. Morbi ac orci et nisl hendrerit mollis. Suspendisse ut massa. Cras nec ante. Pellentesque a nulla. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Aliquam tincidunt urna. Nulla ullamcorper vestibulum turpis. Pellentesque cursus luctus mauris.

December 2011 - June 2013 Sharif CERT Center Java SE/EE Developer C/C++ Developer/Architect

> Nam dui ligula, fringilla a, euismod sodales, sollicitudin vel, wisi. Morbi auctor lorem non justo. Nam lacus libero, pretium at, lobortis vitae, ultricies et, tellus. Donec aliquet, tortor sed accumsan bibendum, erat ligula aliquet magna, vitae ornare odio metus a mi. Morbi ac orci et nisl hendrerit mollis. Suspendisse ut massa. Cras nec ante. Pellentesque a nulla. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Aliquam tincidunt urna. Nulla ullamcorper vestibulum turpis. Pellentesque cursus luctus mauris.

October 2011 - June 2012 Sharif Engineering Process Development Co. C++/Qt Developer

Nam dui ligula, fringilla a, euismod sodales, sollicitudin vel, wisi. Morbi auctor lorem non justo. Nam lacus libero, pretium at, lobortis vitae, ultricies et, tellus. Donec aliquet, tortor sed accumsan bibendum, erat ligula aliquet magna, vitae ornare odio metus a mi. Morbi ac orci et nisl hendrerit mollis. Suspendisse ut massa. Cras nec ante. Pellentesque a nulla. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Aliquam tincidunt urna. Nulla ullamcorper vestibulum turpis. Pellentesque cursus luctus mauris.

Kamran Amini

Mobile: (+98) 935 45 92 265 Email: kam.cpp@gmail.com

September 2009 - August 2011 Septa Co.

## C#.NET Developer/Architect

Nam dui ligula, fringilla a, euismod sodales, sollicitudin vel, wisi. Morbi auctor lorem non justo. Nam lacus libero, pretium at, lobortis vitae, ultricies et, tellus. Donec aliquet, tortor sed accumsan bibendum, erat ligula aliquet magna, vitae ornare odio metus a mi. Morbi ac orci et nisl hendrerit mollis. Suspendisse ut massa. Cras nec ante. Pellentesque a nulla. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Aliquam tincidunt urna. Nulla ullamcorper vestibulum turpis. Pellentesque cursus luctus mauris.

2007 - 2009 Aramin IT Co. C++ Developer/Architect

Nam dui ligula, fringilla a, euismod sodales, sollicitudin vel, wisi. Morbi auctor lorem non justo. Nam lacus libero, pretium at, lobortis vitae, ultricies et, tellus. Donec aliquet, tortor sed accumsan bibendum, erat ligula aliquet magna, vitae ornare odio metus a mi. Morbi ac orci et nisl hendrerit mollis. Suspendisse ut massa. Cras nec ante. Pellentesque a nulla. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Aliquam tincidunt urna. Nulla ullamcorper vestibulum turpis. Pellentesque cursus luctus mauris.

EDUCATION		
SKILLS		

## **HOBBIES**